But all these charges are false, Your Highness.
这些指控都是假的, 殿下
We are not attacking Draconian ships. We never have!
我们没有攻击龙族的船, 从来没有
Our soldiers have seen the Earthmen attack us.
我们士兵倒看见过地球人攻击我们
Our cargos have been stolen.
我们的货物被偷走
We are Draconians, we do not lie.
我们是龙族人, 我们不撒谎
The honour of your race is well known, Your Highness.
你们种族的名声是众所周知的, 殿下
That is why I cannot understand your actions.
这也是为什么我弄不明白你们的行动
Actions?
行动?
You attack our ships, you steal their cargoes,
你们攻击我们的船, 你们抢走他们的货物
you ignore our protests and just meet them with these counter-charges.
你忽略我们的抗议, 只是提出这些反诉
Our charges are true but yours are false.
我们的指控是真实的, 但你们的是假的
We do not attack your ships.
我们不会攻击你们的船
Well, I'm never going in that thing again.
我可再也不进去那里了
Oh, come on, Jo, be reasonable.
哦, 得了, Jo, 理性一点
Only you could manage to have a traffic accident in space.
只有你能在太空当中制造一场交通事故
- Well, we didn't hit it, did we? - Didn't we? Where's this then?
- 不过, 我们并没有撞上, 对吧? - 没有? 那这里是哪里?
Well, by a rather brilliant last-minute course correction,
这个嘛, 在最后紧急关头, 凭着我漂亮的修正
I've managed to materialise the TARDIS inside the spaceship.
我把 TARDIS 开到了这艘飞船的内部
But to avoid hitting it,
但为了避免跟它相撞
I've had to make a random jump back into normal space.
我不得不跳回了普通空间
Terrific, but what do we do now?
挺棒, 但我们现在做什么
Well, if I'm to get us back to Earth, I'd better find out where we are.
唔, 如果我要把我们带回地球, 我最好要先搞清楚我们在哪里
I'll just go and check the instruments.
我去检查一下仪器
HARDY: You won't believe this.
你不会相信的
- Now what? - Maybe it's a wreck.
- 现在怎么办? - 可能是艘废船
Try and make contact. They may need help.
试着联系一下, 他们可能需要帮助
This is Earth cargo ship C982 in close proximity to you.
我们是地球货船C982, 就在你们旁边
Do you read me? Do you read me?
你们能听到吗? 你们能听到吗?
(WHITE NOISE OVER RADIO)
- Try again. - Do you read me?
- 再试试  - 你们能听到吗?
Are you in need of assistance?
你们是否需要协助?
(WHITE NOISE OVER RADIO)
It's a weird-looking crate.
这箱子看起来真奇怪
(HIGH PITCHED BLEEPING)
Draconians!
龙族人!
- Doctor? - Well, I think I know where we are.
- 博士? - 我想我知道我们在哪儿了
I've got a pretty good idea about when.
而且对于我们在何时也基本清楚了
- Come and take a look at this. - A look at what?
- 过来看一下这个 - 看看什么?
That.
那个
Well, it's just a spaceship, Jo.
只是一艘飞船, Jo
Now, I reckon we must be somewhere in the 26th century.
现在我估计我们肯定在26世纪的某处
Well, interstellar travel's pretty routine by now.
在这个时代, 星际旅行已经比较普遍了
A moment ago, it seemed to change shape.
就此刚才, 它好像在变形
- Hmm? - It was when I heard that noise.
- 嗯? - 就是那时我听到那个声音的
Didn't you hear it?
你没有听到吗?
Well, I did hear something but very faintly.
我也听到点声音, 但比较微弱
Come on, Jo. Let's go and find the crew.
这儿来, Jo. 我们去找找船员
I want to find the exact date for my calculations.
我想去问问具体的日子, 看看我的计算对不对
- HARDY: They're going to attack us! - STEWART: Get the blasters.
- 他们要攻击我们 - 去拿枪
HARDY: You can't take on a battle cruiser!
你没法打赢一艘战斗巡航舰
Get the blasters!
去拿枪!
Emergency, emergency, red alert.
紧急情况, 紧急情况, 红色警报
This is Earth cargo ship C982
这里是地球货船C982
on coordinate 8972/6483.
目前在坐标8972/6483
We are under attack by a Draconian battle cruiser, galaxy class,
我们正被一艘龙族战斗巡航舰攻击, 星系级
equipped with neutronic missiles.
装备有中子导弹
Emergency, emergency!
紧急情况, 紧急情况
Oh, how do you do? I'm sorry about this intrusion.
哦, 你好, 很抱歉这样闯进来
HARDY: Who are you?
你是谁!
(HIGH-PITCHED BLEEPING)
DOCTOR: I said how do you do?
HARDY: Dragons!
- 我说了你好 - 龙!
- Drop that gun. - Gun?
- 把枪扔掉 - 枪?
I haven't got a gun. This is simply my hand.
我没有枪, 这只是我的手
(GASPING) No!
不!
-DOCTOR: Jo, what's the matter with you? - He's a Drashig!
- Jo, 你怎么了? - 这是个 Drashig!
DOCTOR: Nonsense, it's simply a man with a gun.
Now pull yourself together.
别胡说, 只是一个普通人拿了一把枪. 冷静一点
(注: Jo 所看见的怪物名叫 Drashig , 这是在上一个故事 Carnival of Monsters 首次出现的一种猎食怪物)
This is Earth cargo ship C982.
这里是地球货船C982
Situation, red alert.
状态, 红色警报
Draconian battle cruiser about to lock on now.
龙族战斗巡航舰即将对接上我们的船
All anti-boarding procedures carried out.
所有反登船措施已经实施
Awaiting instructions. Out.
等待指示. 完毕
This is the commander of the Draconian battle cruiser.
我是龙族战斗巡航舰的指挥官
We are locked onto your vessel
我们已经对接上你们的船只
and are about to board.
即将登船
If you offer any resistance,
如果你们进行任何抵抗
you will be destroyed.
你们将会被消灭
Open the hatch of your airlock.
打开你们减压舱的舱门
I found these two Dragons in the hold.
我在货舱里找到了这两条龙
But that's impossible. They... They're only just locking on.
这不可能啊, 他们才刚刚对接上
Doctor, what's happening? What's going on?
博士, 发生了什么? 什么情况?
I'm not sure, Jo. Something rather intriguing.
我不确定, Jo. 有点奇怪
If you resist, we can destroy you with our neutronic weapons.
如果你们反抗, 我们能用我们的中子武器消灭你们
If you destroy our ship, you won't get the cargo.
如果你摧毁我们的飞船, 你就得不到货物了
Oh, so that's what it's all about.
哦, 原来是为了这个
Open the hatch to your airlock
打开你们减压舱的舱门
or we shall enter your ship by force.
否则我们要采用武力进入了
- We refuse. - They can blow us to pieces!
- 我们拒绝执行 - 他们会把我们轰成碎片的
I've sent a message to Earth asking for help.
我已经给地球发信息求救了
This is a transcript of a distress call from one of our ships.
这是有记录, 抄录自我们一艘船说发出的求救信号
"From Earth's cargo ship number C982 on coordinate 8972/6483.
"来自地球货船, 编号C982, 坐标 8972/6483
"We are under attack by a Draconian battle cruiser,
我们正被一艘龙族战斗巡航舰攻击
"galaxy class, equipped with neutronic missiles."
星系级, 配备有中子导弹
The treaty between our two empires established a frontier in space.
我们两个帝国通过协商建立了一个太空边界
We have never violated that frontier.
我们来从来没有违反过这个条约
You have invaded our part of the galaxy many times.
但你们已经数次入侵我们星系
In pursuit of your ships when they have raided ours!
FIXME
We've been very patient, perhaps too patient.
我们一直很有耐性, 也许是太有耐性了
General Williams!
Williams 将军!
I take it a rescue attempt has been mounted?
我认为已经在安排营救了吧?
We've established an automatic procedure,
我们已经一套自动化过程
because of the frequency of these attacks.
因为这种攻击已经变得很频繁了
Then I suggest you go and supervise the matter.
那我建议你离开, 去监控好营救过程
There's no need.
这并没有必要
Please do as I say.
请按我说的做
As you wish, Madam President.
听您的吩咐, 总统夫人
Your general is insolent.
你的将军太无礼了
We know the hatred he has always felt for our people.
我们都知道他一直都对我们种族怀着仇恨
Long ago he caused war.
很久以前他挑起了战争
Now he wishes to do so again.
现在他还打算再来一次
He's a soldier, Your Highness, and he's angry.
他是个战士, 殿下, 而且他很愤怒
The people of Earth are angry.
地球人都很愤怒
So are the nobles of my father's court!
我父亲的王廷上那些贵族也一样!
I must ask you to take my personal appeal to your father, the Emperor.
我必须得让你把我个人的呼吁带给你父皇
He must put a stop to these attacks.
他必须叫停这些攻击
If Draconia has some grievances against Earth,
如果龙族对地球有什么不满
then this is not the way to deal with them.
这也并不是处理问题的正确做法
Many of our noblemen felt it was a mistake
to make a treaty with the Earthmen.
我们贵族中的许多人认为跟地球人缔结条约是一个错误
Perhaps they were right.
也许他们是对的
You attack our ships and when we protest
你们攻击了我们的飞船, 当我们提出抗议的时候
you trick us with lies and evasions.
你们又用谎言和否认来欺骗我们
I give you a final warning.
我给你们最后的警告
The path you are treading leads only to war.
你们走的这条路只会通向战争
And in that war, Draconia will destroy you!
而在这场战争里, 龙族人会摧毁你们
(HISSING)
They'll be through that door any minute!
他们马上就能穿过那个门了
Doctor, what are you doing?
博士, 你在做什么?
I'm reversing the polarity of my ultrasonic screwdriver's power source,
我在把音速起子上电源的极性翻转过来
thereby converting it into an extremely powerful electromagnet.
这样它就变成了一个极强的电磁铁
Oh. What good will that do?
哦, 那又有什么用呢?
You wait and see, Jo.
你等着看吧, Jo
Is it working?
这能行吗?
(LOCK GRATING)
Yes, I think so.
是的, 我觉得可以
- I'm going to get the prisoners. - What for?
- 我去把囚犯带出来 - 带出来做什么?
We're using them as hostages, remember?
我们可以用他们作为人质, 记得吧?
You'd better be quick about it. We haven't got much time.
你最好动作快点, 我们没有太多时间
- How is it going? - Nearly there.
- 进展怎么样 - 快好了
(LOCK GRATING)
There you are, that's it.
搞定了, 就是这样
Oh, how very embarrassing.  Good afternoon.
哦, 好尴尬啊. 下午好
- Out. - That's just where we were going.
- 出来 - 我们正打算出来呢
We're going to meet your friends.
我们去见见你们的朋友
- Come on! Get up there! - Come on, they're almost through.
- 快点, 上这里来! - 快点, 他们快打穿了
HARDY: Get in front! If your friends start shooting,
they'll get you first.
站前面去! 如果你的朋友们开始开枪, 先射死的是你们
- But they're not our friends! - You are part of their boarding party.
- 但他们不是我们的朋友! - 你们俩是他们登船小队的成员
They haven't boarded yet. They're still breaking through that door.
他们还没有登船. 他们还在切割舱门呢
- Now, try and be logical, man. - They're coming through!
- 能不能讲点理, 伙计 - 他们过来了
- Ogrons! - DOCTOR: Back to the TARDIS, Jo. Back!
- Ogrons!  - 快回到 TARDIS, Jo. 回去!
Doctor! Doctor!
博士, 博士!
JO: (SOFTLY) Doctor?
博士?
- Jo? - JO: Doctor!
- Jo? - 博士?
- Jo? - JO: Doctor, I'm over here.
- Jo? - 博士, 我在这里
All right, Jo, what are you doing in there?
好, Jo, 你在那里面干什么
Oh, Doctor, thank goodness, you're all right.
哦, 博士, 感谢神灵, 你没事
I thought they'd killed you.
我以为他们杀了你
Come on, come and sit down.
来吧, 过来坐下
Must have been some kind of neuronic stun gun.
肯定是某种中子击晕枪
I wonder why they didn't kill me? What exactly happened, Jo?
很奇怪他们为什么没杀了我? 到底发生了什么, Jo?
Well, they took the cargo, threw me in here and...
呃..他们把货拿走了, 然后把我扔到这里面就...
- Doctor? - Hmm?
- 博士 - 唔?
- They also took the TARDIS. - Oh...
- 他们还带走了 TARDIS - 噢...
Oh, we're stranded. What are we going to do?
哦, 我们陷入困境了. 现在怎么办?
Well, try and get the TARDIS back, of course.
当然是想办法把 TARDIS 弄回来
(JO SIGHS)
Why should the Ogrons attack this ship?
为什么 Ogrons 要攻击这艘船?
- To steal the cargo. - No. No, there's more to it than that.
- 为了偷货呗 - 不, 不, 远不仅于此
That... That sound that you heard,
那个...你听到的那个声音
it's all too sophisticated for the Ogrons.
对于 Ogrons 来说过于复杂了
- Well, they're gone now. - Yeah, the question is, where?
- 他们现在已经走了 - 对, 但问题是, 去了哪儿?
Hey, Doctor, last time we met the Ogrons
嘿, 博士, 上一次我们碰到 Ogrons 的时候
they were working for the Daleks, right?
他们在为 Daleks 卖命, 对不?
- Well, you don't suppose that that... - No, no, not necessarily.
- 这, 你不是想说... - 不, 不, 不一定
No, the Ogrons are mercenaries.
不, 这些 Ogrons 都是雇佣兵
Other life forms use them to do their dirty work.
其他的种族会用他们来干些脏活
Come on, Jo, let's go and find the crew.
来吧, Jo, 我们去看看能不能找到船员
(博士与 Jo 上一次碰到 Ogrons 是在09x01 The Day of the Daleks 这集,
所以这次 Ogrons 这次一露面, Jo 就能认出他们了)
Take a look at that one.
你看一下那个
DOCTOR: It's all right, Jo. We're being rescued.
没事了, Jo. 我们得救了
- What happened? - Well, don't worry, old chap.
- 发生了什么? - 别担心, 老伙计
You'll be all right now. I think...
你很快就没事了, 我想...
Draconians! They're boarding!
龙族人! 他们要上船了!
- Stewart? Who are you? - Passengers.
- Stewart? 你们是谁?  - 乘客
I see. Having a fancy dress party? What happened?
我明白了, 在开化妆舞会? 刚才什么情况?
- Dragons attacked us. - Did they get the cargo?
- 那些龙袭击了我们 - 他们劫走货物了没
- I don't know. - Yes, they took everything.
- 我不清楚 - 是的, 他们全拿走了
Including some rather valuable property of mine.
包括我个人的一些相当值钱的东西
- Well, tough luck. - Oh, thank you very much.
- 这样啊, 挺倒霉啊 - 哦, 很感谢你们
- Dragons... They attacked us. - Yes, we know.
- 那些龙...他们攻击了我们 - 是的, 我们知道了
You say you're passengers.
Isn't that a little unusual on a cargo ship?
你说你们是乘客, 这对于一艘货船来讲是不是有点不合常理啊?
Well, we're here, aren't we?
但是, 我们现在就在这里, 对不?
Where did you pick these two up?
你们在哪里捎带上他们俩的?
I don't know. I can't seem to remember...
我不知道, 好像想不起来了...
Pull yourself together! How did they get on board?
站好了! 他们是怎么上船的?
Stowaways... That's it, they were stowaways.
偷渡的... 对了, 他们是偷渡的
- They were sending messages. - That's right.
- 他们曾经往外发送信息 - 那就对了
They were helping the Dragons. They're traitors!
他们在帮助那些龙, 他们是叛徒!